JULIUS OGUNNIYI

22, Bolarin Street, Off Pab Bustop, Ikotun-Egbe, Lagos, Nigeria. +2349024420929
ogunniyi.julius12@gmail.com · ng.linkedin.com/in/julius-ogunniyi-97884b199 · myportfoliomurex.vercel.app/

PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

Tech-savvy Frontend Developer with comprehensive experience of 2 years of developing websites. Passionate and hardworking to deliver dynamic interfaces and clean code on deadlines, strong in HTML, CSS and JavaScript and also template creation websites (Wordpress, weebly). Detailed understanding of complex, up-to-date programming languages and considerations.

EXPERIENCE

Makintouch Consulting – Front End Web Designer Feb 2022 – Present.

- Created custom websites by harnessing HTML, CSS, and JavaScript skills.
- Improved website navigation with clear and intuitive UX mapping.
- Integrated RESTful API third party app with a movie website.
- Designed web pages to enhance branding and navigation.
- Designed landing pages for the organization's website.
- Reconstructed a whole website using a template creation site (Wordpress).
- Designed Landing page for a Learning Management System.
- Trained students at Neander International College on Web Design (HTML, CSS and Javascript)
- Wrote SEO Blog articles for the website blog to increase the chances of ranking on google.
- Boosted website performance and stability through planned maintenance and targeted troubleshooting.

Freelance - Front End Developer March 2021 – January 2022.

- Converted User Interface designs into functional web applications
- Worked with a team of Mobile App Engineers and Back End Engineer to achieve a project.
- Worked with HTML, CSS, JavaScript and Jquery.
- Developed websites using React.js and Vanilla CSS.
- Developed websites using React.js, FontAwesome and Tailwindcss

Makintouch Consulting - System Administrator/Junior Web Developer March 2020 - October 2020.

- Configured, tested and maintained network equipment.
- Planned and implemented upgrades to system hardware and software.
- Resolved issues and escalated problems with knowledgeable support and quality service.
- Worked with users to determine areas in need of improvement.
- Implemented, maintained, developed and tested the installation and update of file servers, print servers and application servers in all departments.
- I was also working with the senior full stack developer and learning web design.
- Worked on the organization website with wordpress, developed some basic websites using HTML, CSS and Bootstrap.

CERTIFICATES OF TRAINING

- Web Development HIIT PLC (July August, 2019).
- CompTIA A+ (September, 2020).

EDUCATION

Academic Qualifications

- **Bowen University, Iwo, Osun state** B.Sc. In Computer Science and Information Technology (**September, 2017 November 2021**).
- Lagos State Senior Model College, Badore, Ajah, Lagos West Africa Senior School Certificate Examination (June 2017).

SKILLS

- HTML5
- Vanilla CSS
- JavaScript
- Tailwindcss
- SASS
- React-Bootstrap
- Jquery
- React.js

LANGUAGES SPOKEN

• English, Yoruba.

INTERESTS

- Coding
- Music
- Video games

REFERENCES

Available on request.

- React Native
- Node.js
- RESTful API
- Web development projects
- Template Creation sites (WordPress, Weebly)
- Graphics Design
- Git/Github
- Search Engine Optimization